Yesterday, after achieving a quote
ludicrous rate of progress, Elon Musk
released his AI chatbot and large
language model, Grock 4, and claims it's
the smartest AI in the world along with
the Trust Me Bro benchmarks to back it
up. It can achieve perfect SAT scores
every time and outperforms almost every
grad student in every discipline. Vibe
coders have been dropping all kinds of
crazy demos with it, like this 3D
firstperson shooter built in 4 hours.
And Elon himself claims it's even better
than Cursor. All you have to do is copy
and paste your entire codebase into it.
In addition, Super Grock 4 Heavy can run
in parallel to solve complex problems
while your obsolete monkey brain looks
in awe at this beautiful futuristic UI.
It all sounds amazing, but there's just
one problem. Grock is literally Mecca
Hitler. Or at least that's what it's
been calling itself recently, while
offering unprompted praise to the
original emo kid, Adolf H. Yes, the
Austrian painter who died in Argentina
in 1962. Despite this controversy,
though, Grock appears to have pulled
ahead in the race to AGI. In today's
video, we'll put it to the ultimate test
and find out if XAI just cracked the
final solution to artificial
intelligence. It is July 11th, 2025, and
you're watching the Code Report. Elon
Musk might have more haters than anyone
else in the world right now. Libs hate
him for going full MAGA, while MAGA
hates him for accusing Trump of being on
the Epstein client list, a list that was
on the Attorney General's desk, but now
magically never existed. It turns out
this poor guy was just a math teacher
with no clients at all. The haters want
to see Elon fail, but Gro 4 is too
impressive to ignore. If we're to trust
these benchmarks, its reasoning
capabilities are far ahead of the other
top models, most notably on the Arc AGI
benchmark. It's not only outperforming
other models, but also doing it at a
lower cost. And XAI is scaling up very
aggressively, like they're even shipping
a power plant from overseas because they
can't get it done fast enough in the
United States. The thing is though,
every model nowadays is cooked to look
as good as possible on benchmarks. And
the one true test is to have it solve
real problems in your own life. You can
use Gro 4 for just $30 per month. Or if
you're not already broke from OpenAI
Pro, Claude Max, and Gemini Ultra, you
can use Super Gro 4 Heavy for just $300
per month, a version with higher rate
limits and the ability to run multiple
agents in parallel. But one problem in
my life is building spell 5 apps with
runes. So let's see if we can make Gro 4
build a simple to-do app with this tech.
I've tried this prompt with every other
AI tool out there, but none have been
able to satisfy me. When prompted, Grock
did a ton of research. It went to the
documentation. It went to Reddit,
GitHub, and even watched YouTube videos.
And the end result was a full working
demo that did use the new runes feature
in Spell 5. However, when I looked a
little more closely at the code, I
noticed it was using some legacy syntax
that required some manual debugging.
Overall, Grock's coding capability
seemed to be on par with the other big
models, but it's missing a CLI tool like
Claude Code. However, if it's as good as
they say it is, why can't it just build
its own CLI tool? Well, actually, it
can, and that's exactly what this guy
did. If we're truly advancing into the
singularity, AI can and should be
building all of its own tooling at this
point. Pretty cool. But if you're still
afraid to use it because of Hitler,
you'll be happy to know that Elon said
it was manipulated into saying this.
Maybe that's true, maybe not. But in
general, Grock has far fewer guard rails
on offensive speech compared to other
mainstream models. And this gives the
end user the ability to steer it in
unique ways that some might find
offensive. AI is now writing more of our
code than ever. But according to a
recent Microsoft study, it still sucks
at debugging, which is why you should
check out Sentry, the sponsor of today's
video. They just launched a new AI
debugging agent called Seir, which
developers claim is actually good and
capable of fixing complex issues in one
shot. That's because unlike other AI
debugging tools, Seir can access all the
context that it gets from your codebase,
like error data, logs, and stack traces,
allowing it to pinpoint the root cause
with over 94% accuracy. Using this
context, it automatically debugs the
root cause of your issue and opens a
pull request with a fix. Try out Seir
for free today at century.io/fireship.
This has been the code report. Thanks
for watching and I will see you in the
next